<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">18195059</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2008</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0066-4804</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>52</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2008</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Antimicrobial agents and chemotherapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Antimicrob Agents Chemother</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Caspofungin prolongs survival of transiently neutropenic rats with advanced-stage invasive pulmonary aspergillosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1345</StartPage><EndPage>1350</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1345-50</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/AAC.00536-07</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>A high-dose-step-down strategy for caspofungin treatment was evaluated in an experimental model of advanced-stage invasive pulmonary aspergillosis. The therapeutic efficacy of caspofungin in relation to the severity of invasive pulmonary infection caused by Aspergillus fumigatus in transiently neutropenic rats was investigated by using rat survival and the decrease in the fungal burden as the parameters of efficacy. When treatment was started at either 16 h or 24 h after fungal inoculation, caspofungin administered intraperitoneally at 4 mg/kg of body weight/day for 10 days was highly effective (100% and 93% rat survival, respectively). However, only 27% rat survival was obtained when treatment was started at 72 h, when the rats had advanced-stage infection. Increasing the dose from 4 to 10 mg/kg/day could compensate for the decrease in efficacy and resulted in 67% rat survival. The high dose of 10 mg/kg/day for 10 days did not appear to be necessary since a high-dose-step-down dosing schedule with 10 mg/kg/day for 3 days followed by 4 mg/kg/day for 7 days was equally effective. At 10 days after the end of treatment with 10 mg/kg/day caspofungin, the level of neither A. fumigatus DNA nor A. fumigatus galactomannan in the infected left lung was significantly decreased. In contrast, A. fumigatus galactomannan concentrations in serum were significantly decreased. The levels of creatinine, blood urea nitrogen, alanine aminotransferase, and asparate aminotransferase were not elevated during treatment. Caspofungin is effective for the treatment of invasive pulmonary aspergillosis in transiently neutropenic rats and is even effective in rats with advanced-stage infection. In this model, the administration of high-dose-step-down treatment was as effective as treatment with high doses for the whole treatment period.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van de Sande</LastName><ForeName>Wendy W J</ForeName><Initials>WW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Erasmus MC, University Medical Center Rotterdam, Department of Medical Microbiology &amp; Infectious Diseases, 's-Gravendijkwal 230, 3015 CE, Rotterdam, The Netherlands. w.vandesande@erasmusmc.nl</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Vianen</LastName><ForeName>Wim</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>ten Kate</LastName><ForeName>Marian T</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vissers</LastName><ForeName>Jolanda</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Laurijsens</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tavakol</LastName><ForeName>Mehri</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rijnders</LastName><ForeName>Bart J A</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mathot</LastName><ForeName>Ron A A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bakker-Woudenberg</LastName><ForeName>Irma A J M</ForeName><Initials>IA</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2008</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Antimicrob Agents Chemother</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0315061</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0066-4804</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000935">Antifungal Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D054714">Echinocandins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D055666">Lipopeptides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>F0XDI6ZL63</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000077336">Caspofungin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000935" MajorTopicYN="N">Antifungal Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000493" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacokinetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001228" MajorTopicYN="N">Aspergillosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="Y">mortality</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001232" MajorTopicYN="N">Aspergillus fumigatus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077336" MajorTopicYN="N">Caspofungin</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054714" MajorTopicYN="N">Echinocandins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000493" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacokinetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055666" MajorTopicYN="N">Lipopeptides</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008168" MajorTopicYN="N">Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008172" MajorTopicYN="N">Lung Diseases, Fungal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="Y">mortality</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009503" MajorTopicYN="N">Neutropenia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="N">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2008</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2008</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2008</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18195059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2292535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00536-07</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">AAC.00536-07</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abruzzo, G. K., C. J. Gill, A. M. Flattery, L. Kong, C. Leighton, J. G. Smith, V. B. Pikounis, K. Bartizal, and H. Rosen. 2000. Efficacy of the echinocandin caspofungin against disseminated aspergillosis and candidiasis in cyclophosphamide-induced immunosuppressed mice. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother. 44:2310-2318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC90063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10952573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker, M. J., S. de Marie, M. H. Fens, H. A. Verbrugh, and I. A. Bakker-Woudenberg. 2003. Effect of amphotericin B treatment on kinetics of cytokines and parameters of fungal load in neutropenic rats with invasive pulmonary aspergillosis. J. Antimicrob. Chemother. 52:428-434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12917249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker, M. J., S. de Marie, D. Willemse, H. A. Verbrugh, and I. A. Bakker-Woudenberg. 2000. Quantitative galactomannan detection is superior to PCR in diagnosing and monitoring invasive pulmonary aspergillosis in an experimental rat model. J. Clin. Microbiol. 38:1434-1438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC86459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10747121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betts, R., A. Glasmacher, J. Maertens, G. Maschmeyer, J. A. Vazquez, H. Teppler, A. Taylor, R. Lupinacci, C. Sable, and N. Kartsonis. 2006. Efficacy of caspofungin against invasive Candida or invasive Aspergillus infections in neutropenic patients. Cancer 106:466-473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16353208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowman, J. C., G. K. Abruzzo, J. W. Anderson, A. M. Flattery, C. J. Gill, V. B. Pikounis, D. M. Schmatz, P. A. Liberator, and C. M. Douglas. 2001. Quantitative PCR assay to measure Aspergillus fumigatus burden in a murine model of disseminated aspergillosis: demonstration of efficacy of caspofungin acetate. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother. 45:3474-3481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC90856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11709327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemons, K. V., R. A. Sobel, and D. A. Stevens. 2000. Toxicity of LY303366, an echinocandin antifungal, in mice pretreated with glucocorticoids. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother. 44:378-381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC89686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10639365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemons, K. V., and D. A. Stevens. 2006. Efficacy of micafungin alone or in combination against experimental pulmonary aspergillosis. Med. Mycol. 44:69-73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16805095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Council of the European Commission. 1986. Guidelines on the protection of experimental animals. European Commission, Brussels, Belgium.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontaine, T., C. Simenel, G. Dubreucq, O. Adam, M. Delepierre, J. Lemoine, C. E. Vorgias, M. Diaquin, and J. P. Latge. 2000. Molecular organization of the alkali-insoluble fraction of Aspergillus fumigatus cell wall. J. Biol. Chem. 275:27594-27607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10869365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groll, A. H., D. Mickiene, R. Petraitiene, V. Petraitis, C. A. Lyman, J. S. Bacher, S. C. Piscitelli, and T. J. Walsh. 2001. Pharmacokinetic and pharmacodynamic modeling of anidulafungin (LY303366): reappraisal of its efficacy in neutropenic animal models of opportunistic mycoses using optimal plasma sampling. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother. 45:2845-2855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC90741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11557479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maertens, J., I. Raad, G. Petrikkos, M. Boogaerts, D. Selleslag, F. B. Petersen, C. A. Sable, N. A. Kartsonis, A. Ngai, A. Taylor, T. F. Patterson, D. W. Denning, and T. J. Walsh. 2004. Efficacy and safety of caspofungin for treatment of invasive aspergillosis in patients refractory to or intolerant of conventional antifungal therapy. Clin. Infect. Dis. 39:1563-1571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15578352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maschmeyer, G., and A. Glasmacher. 2005. Pharmacological properties and clinical efficacy of a recently licensed systemic antifungal, caspofungin. Mycoses 48:227-234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15982202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison, V. A. 2006. Echinocandin antifungals: review and update. Expert. Rev. Anti-Infect. Ther. 4:325-342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16597212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petraitiene, R., V. Petraitis, A. H. Groll, T. Sein, R. L. Schaufele, A. Francesconi, J. Bacher, N. A. Avila, and T. J. Walsh. 2002. Antifungal efficacy of caspofungin (MK-0991) in experimental pulmonary aspergillosis in persistently neutropenic rabbits: pharmacokinetics, drug disposition, and relationship to galactomannan antigenemia. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother. 46:12-23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC127008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11751105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petraitis, V., R. Petraitiene, A. H. Groll, A. Bell, D. P. Callender, T. Sein, R. L. Schaufele, C. L. McMillian, J. Bacher, and T. J. Walsh. 1998. Antifungal efficacy, safety, and single-dose pharmacokinetics of LY303366, a novel echinocandin B, in experimental pulmonary aspergillosis in persistently neutropenic rabbits. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother. 42:2898-2905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC105963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9797223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone, J. A., S. D. Holland, P. J. Wickersham, A. Sterrett, M. Schwartz, C. Bonfiglio, M. Hesney, G. A. Winchell, P. J. Deutsch, H. Greenberg, T. L. Hunt, and S. A. Waldman. 2002. Single- and multiple-dose pharmacokinetics of caspofungin in healthy men. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother. 46:739-745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC127465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11850256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Doornum, G. J., J. Guldemeester, A. D. Osterhaus, and H. G. Niesters. 2003. Diagnosing herpesvirus infections by real-time amplification and rapid culture. J. Clin. Microbiol. 41:576-580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC149665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12574249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Vianen, W., S. de Marie, M. T. ten Kate, R. A. Mathot, and I. A. Bakker-Woudenberg. 2006. Caspofungin: antifungal activity in vitro, pharmacokinetics, and effects on fungal load and animal survival in neutropenic rats with invasive pulmonary aspergillosis. J. Antimicrob. Chemother. 57:732-740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16464895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh, T. J., H. Teppler, G. R. Donowitz, J. A. Maertens, L. R. Baden, A. Dmoszynska, O. A. Cornely, M. R. Bourque, R. J. Lupinacci, C. A. Sable, and B. E. dePauw. 2004. Caspofungin versus liposomal amphotericin B for empirical antifungal therapy in patients with persistent fever and neutropenia. N. Engl. J. Med. 351:1391-1402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15459300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>